现今
♪ Lose Control - 林俊杰 ♪
♪ In The Dark - Swae Lee, Jhene Aiko ♪
♪ Act Up - Rich Brian, EARTHGANG ♪
♪ Run It - DJ SNAKE, Rick Ross, Rich Brian ♪
♪ Swan Song - SAWEETIE, NIKI ♪
♪ Fire In The Sky - ANDERSON .PAAK ♪
十环帮将会回归
声明：关于网络上与本片相关的争议与传言 本字幕组不持任何立场
字幕翻译仅为没有办法观看到本片的观众提供判断传言真假的机会
请各位观众观看完之后自行判断 判断的结果是大家自己的事
若出现版权争议 本字幕组会及时下架资源
远鉴字幕组制作
[Visionary] 0day-sub
翻译  FergieTao 筱雪 方长 Addison
翻译  fantasticboy521 子將 MY. Yves
翻译  Angrybaby Chris_Elsker_Dig Jenny
翻译  NIL 小芋 一个大窝瓜 拉文克劳院花
翻译  今天吃冰激凌了 二三里 辰哥哥 落云
校对  Jenny 徐妙妙 AaZUSA
总监  Hydra小可爱 NightKingslayerW
翻译  泰勒斯迷弟 juicy 温室老虎（已黑化）
若有意参与热门影视剧的字幕译制
（例如鹰眼第一季 洛基第一季）让自己的名字出现在字幕开头
远鉴字幕组招新群 483552098
招募英语翻译 欢迎您的加入
欢迎关注 b站up主：远鉴字幕组
公众号：远鉴影视 微博：@远鉴字幕组v
欢迎关注 微博资源博主：@苏苏IFA
十环的传说
The legend of the ten rings
已经流传了上千年
has been told for thousands of years.
不论这个故事如何演变
Every generation, the story grows.
它的主人公永远都是同一个人
But at its centre there is always one man.
有人说他的十环是火山口里捡来的 还有人说是墓穴里盗来的
Some say he found the rings in a crater or stole them from a tomb.
它们给了他神一般的力量
They gave him the strength of a god,
也赋予了他长生不老的魔法
and the gift of eternal life.
他本可借着十环之力来惩恶扬善
He could have used them for good.
但他想要的
But all he wanted...
只有征服
was power.
他打造了一支十环军团
He called his army The Ten Rings
千百年来 他们扫荡了世界的每个角落
Over the centuries, they spread into every corner of the world.
他们潜伏于暗处
They moved in the shadows...
颠覆各方政权
Toppled governments...
也改写了历史
And changed the course of history.
凭借着十环之力 他早已称霸千年
He chased money and power for a thousand years.
但他却还不满足
But he still wanted more.
听过塔罗的传说吗
Have you heard the legend of Ta Lo?
一个隐世的村庄 在那里神奇的功法代代相传
A hidden village with mythical creatures and ancient magic.
传说中的神兽和古老的法术还都存在
Where people practise a martial arts style from the gods.
我要找到这个地方
I want to find it.
明白 我这就派侦察队去一探究竟
Of course. I'll send a scout to explore the area,
然后有消息立马跟您汇报
and come back with more information.
我们现在就去
I want to go now.
竹林在
The forest...
正在动
...is moving
这世上再也没有可以让他征服的地方了
He had nothing left on Earth to conquer.
于是他找上了我的家乡
That's when he came for my home.
塔罗的入口在哪
Where's the entrance to Ta Lo?
我们村庄不欢迎你
You're not welcome in our village.
你好像不知道我是谁
You don't know who you're talking to.
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
走吧 不要自找麻烦
Turn around now, and I won't have to hurt you.
就这点本事
Is that all?
那是我第一次见到你的父亲
That was the first time I met your father.
我从没想过自己会为他动心
He was the last person I thought I'd fall for.
但爱总是自有安排
But love had other plans.
尚气
Shang-Chi,
十环的传说啊 讲都讲不完
there's much more to know about the legend of the rings,
等你长大了 自然就会了解的
but you'll learn about that when you're older.
可爸爸的十环那么厉害 你是怎么打败他的
If Dad's rings were so powerful, how did you beat him?
妈妈的故乡塔罗 有一个神龙 它是我们的保护神 它将魔法赋予在了我们每个人的身上
Where I'm from, we are empowered by the magic of the Great Protector.
当你领悟了神龙之心
When you have the heart of our dragon,
你就可以做很多了不起的事情
you can do some amazing things.
那你现在还有魔法吗
Can you still do those things?
妈妈离开的时候啊 把魔法还给了神龙
I left those powers in Ta Lo with our dragon,
但是妈妈得到的更宝贵
but what I got in return is so much better
这个给你
I want you to have this.
如果有一天你迷路了
Whenever you feel lost,
它会帮你找到回家的路
this will help you find your way home.
记住了吗
Can you remember that?
呃
Okay.
先生您好
Hello, sir,
欢迎光临费尔蒙特...
welcome to the Fairmont...
我来开车
I'm driving.
不行 凯蒂
No, you're not... Katy.
嘿 嘿 回来
Hey, hey, get back here.
钥匙给我
Give me the key.
请开门
Please open the door
听听这引擎
My God
- 下车  - 你上车
-Get out. -You get in!
听着 要是出了什么问题
Look, if happens to this thing,
我们都得失业
we're gonna be jobless
而且下半辈子都得还债了
and in debt for the rest of our lives.
拜托 不会有事的
Come on. Nothing's gonna happen to this car.
我是亚洲杰夫·戈登
I'm the Asian Jeff Gordon.
我不认识这个人
I don't know who that is.
全美改装车竞赛历史上获奖最多的人
Most career wins in all of NASCAR history?
请你下车
Please get out of the car.
尚恩
Shaun,
我们已经是10年老朋友了 好吗
we've been friends for 10 years, okay?
你也清楚 我又不笨
You know I'm not an idiot.
上车吧 我会慢慢开的
Please, get in. I'll go slow.
凯蒂 小心...
Katy, watch the...
高中时第一次见到凯蒂
I knew Katy was trouble
我就知道她是一个惹事精
the first day we met in high school.
当时我总被人欺负...
I was getting picked on a lot,.
我们都总会因为各种原因被人欺负
-for all the reasons we all get picked on a lot
况且我才到美国
Plus, I had just moved to the US,
英语也不好
so I was struggling with my English,
记得有一天我在去吃午饭的路上
and I was on my way to lunch one day
有个体型比我大一圈的人
when this guy who was like twice my size
在走廊另一头大喊
yells at me from down the hall,
"哟 江南Style"
"What's up, Gangnam Style?"
然后我喊回去 "白痴 我不是韩国人"
So I yelled back, "I'm not Korean, idiot."
我站在角落
And I turn the corner,
看到那男的把书包一放
and I see this guy drop his backpack,
满脸怒气
he's getting all up in his face...
准备给我来上一拳 就在这时
And right before he was about to throw the first punch,
凯蒂不知道从哪儿冒出来
Katy comes out of nowhere,
站在我们中间 然后开始大喊
steps right between us and starts screaming the lyrics
加州旅馆的歌词
to Hotel California.
什么?
What?
这就是混淆视听的艺术 对笨蛋非常有效
It's the art of confusion. Works great on stupid people.
我们就是这样认识的
And that's how we met.
然后我把他拉到停车场
Then I pulled him into the parking lot...
凯蒂告诉我
At which point she revealed.
她把那男的野马车钥匙顺走了
that she had also swiped the keys to the guy's Mustang
于是 我们就在附近游车河
Yeah, we went on a little joyride around the block.
当时你妻子也在车里
And your wife was in the car, too.
-真的 你当时在  -什么?
-That's true. You were. -What?
我只是坐在后排而已
I was just in the back seat.
那也是车的一部分
That's a part of the car.
仍然是坐在车里
That's still a part of the car.
你怎么从没说过这件事
How have you never told me this story?
你知道的 你老婆在做律师之前
You know, before she was a lawyer,
可是很狂野的
your girl was pretty wild.
发生什么了
What happened?
我长大了
I grew up.
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
Yeah, what's that supposed to mean?
意思是也许到了某个时候
That maybe there's a point
你就该停止四处兜风享乐
where you're supposed to stop going on joyrides
并开始考虑发挥自己的潜能
and start thinking about living up to your potential.
你是在开玩笑吧 苏
Please tell me you're kidding, Soo.
听着
Look,
我们现在生活着的这个世界
we're now living in a world.
一半的人口
where at any moment.
随时可能消失
half the population can just disappear.
生命如此短暂 如此脆弱
Life's too short and too fragile.
凯蒂 你是个有伯克利荣誉学位的
Katy, you're a valet driver
泊车员
with an honours degree from Berkeley,
尚恩能说四种语言
and Shaun can speak, like, four languages.
你们是我认识的人里最有才华的
You've always been the most talented people I know.
我只是不明白为什么你们害怕
I just don't get why you're scared
把才华用在正事上
to actually use it for something serious.
哇哦
Wow.
你说话像我妈 你打扮得...
You sound like my mom. You also...
也有点像她
dress like her a little bit, too.
你从哪里买的这件衣服 塔尔伯茨（女性服饰品牌）吗
Where's this from, Talbots?
我们才不是在逃避成年呢
We're not running from adulthood.
做自己喜欢的工作怎么就算逃避了
How is it running to have jobs that you actually like?
是啊 这根本说不通
Yeah, that doesn't even make any sense.
难道代客泊车很容易吗
Did you think valet parking is easy?
这大概是史上最具挑战性的工作了
It's like the most challenging job ever.
你得有人际交往能力 驾驶技术
You need people skills, driving skills...
苏连侧方位停车都不会呢
Soo can't even parallel park
现在都快十二点了 我们还要上早班呢
Well, it's almost midnight. We got the early shift.
我们应该负起责任来 该睡觉了
Should probably be responsible, go to sleep.
是啊 我们应该负起责任来 该睡了
Yeah, we can be responsible. We can do that.
或者
Or...
♪由一场魔毯之旅 看尽路旁与地下的奇景♪
Over, sideways and under on a...
♪ 骑着我的马 走上老城路 ♪
Take my horse to the old town road
♪ 我会 ♪
I'm gonna
♪ 闭上双眼 ♪
Close my eyes
♪ 我不想 ♪
I don't wanna...
早上好 陈太太
Morning, Mrs Chen.
她还没好呢
She's not ready yet.
先进来吃点粥等等吧
Come have some joe while you wait.
凯蒂 尚恩来啦
Katy, Shaun's here.
好啦 妈 我一会儿就来
Yeah, Mom, be there in a minute.
瑞华
Ruihua,.
你怎么还没去帮你爸给店里进货
you're supposed to be helping your dad stock the shop
妈妈 我饿着肚子怎么干活 一会儿腿该抽筋了
Mom, I can't work on an empty stomach, my legs get crampy.
怎么不叫尚恩去
Maybe Shaun can help him
他天天都来这里蹭饭吃
instead of just showing up every day to eat our food.
我很乐意帮忙
I'm happy to help.
不用 瑞华该干的活儿 让他自个儿去
No, it's Ruihua's job, let him do it.
外婆
Waipo.
这是外公的座位
That seat's for Waigong.
对不起
Sorry.
今年清明节 我准备给他 他最喜欢的东西
He's getting all his favourite things this year for the Day of the Dead.
您确定外公
Are you sure that Waigong's allowed to take
能在下面享用这些
Funyuns and cigarettes
洋葱圈和香烟吗
back to the afterlife?
他什么都可以吃
He can take anything.
去年我在他的坟前放了一瓶白酒
Last year I put a bottle of whisky on his grave...
第二天 没啦
And it was gone the next morning.
我知道你们觉得我很傻
I know you kids think it's silly.
我们没觉得您傻 外婆
We don't think it's silly, Waipo.
只是知道外公他在天之灵肯定也希望您走出悲伤
We just know Waigong would've wanted you to move on
享受生活
and enjoy your life.
"走出悲伤"是美国人的观念
"Moving on" is an American idea.
你可是个美国妈妈 别忘了
You're American, Mom! Don't forget.
尚恩
Shaun,
我女儿这周有没有"跳槽"的打算呀
did my daughter apply to any new jobs this week?
她很喜欢现在这份工作
She really likes her job.
我俩都是
We both do.
当初外公从湖南大老远过来
Waigong didn't move here from Hunan
可不是为了让你在这儿给人泊车讨生活的
so you could park cars for a living.
这话倒提醒了我
Well, on that note,
咱们再不走就赶不上公交了
I think we're gonna miss our bus.
对不起 我找了个不体面的工作
I'm sorry for my unacceptable job.
昨晚还熬夜通宵
And for staying out late last night,
享受人生
trying to enjoy my life.
但总有一天 你会为我感到骄傲的 我保证
But one day, I'll make you proud, I promise.
我为你骄傲 姐
I'm proud of you, sis.
泊车 超难的
Parking cars is super hard.
谢了老弟
Thanks, bro.
等你考到了驾照
Maybe one day you'll pass your driver's test,
就能跟我一样实现梦想了
live the dream like me.
-尚恩 我们走吧 -走了 外婆
Come on, Shaun, let's go.
你们什么时候结婚
When are you two going to get married?
外婆 我们只是朋友
Waipo, we're just friends.
好吧 走走走
All right. Go, go, go.
瞧瞧那个女生
Look. Look at that. Look at that girl.
她居然在公交车上写论文
She's writing a research paper on a bus.
所以呢
So?
我妈一度幻想从她的阴道里
That is exactly the daughter
能爬出来这种完美女儿
my mom wishes came out of her vagina.
对不起 她人就这样
I'm sorry about her.
怎么了?
How's it goin'?
项链给我
Give me the pendant,
就没有人会受伤
and no one gets hurt.
你认识这家伙?
Do you know this guy?
我听不懂你在说啥 哥们
I don't know what you're talking about, dude.
-嘿 怎么回事 离我远点 -唔喔
- Hey! Get off of me! - Whoa.
你们他妈的有什么毛病?
What is wrong with you, asshole?
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
那就把项链交出来
Then give us the pendant!
你找错人了
You have the wrong guy!
他看起来很能打吗
Does he look like he can fight?
别闹了 大哥
Come on, bro!
你还好吗
You okay?
大家好 这里是克里夫
Yo, what up, y'all? It's your boy Klev,
在公交上为您实时直播
comin' at you live on the bus.
我年轻的时候
I actually did take
练过一点武术
a little bit of martial arts as a youth,
所以我现在试试解说一下这场打斗
so I'm gonna try and grade this fight as we're goin'.
我靠
Holy shit.
你是谁?
Who are you?
兄弟 你可以的
You got this, bro!
额 当我没说
My bad.
不 不 不
No, no, no!
对不起
Sorry.
这他妈到底什么情况
What the hell's going on?
你非得现在问吗
You really wanna talk about this now?
司机不行了
Bus driver is down.
我不会去接盘的
I'm not gonna handle this.
我一开车就被人骂
Every time I've tried to drive a bus, I get yelled at.
滚开 怪人
Go, you freak!
开门 求你
Open the door, please!
后面那节车厢快掉了
The back is about to go.
等我信号 你就向右急转
On my signal, make a hard right.
啥信号?
What signal?
所有人快去前车厢
Everybody to the front now!
走走走走
Go! Go, go, go.
你好啊 你好啊 你也好啊
What's up, y'all? What's up, y'all? What's up, y'all?
你和你妹妹罪有应得
You and your sister deserve what's coming.
大家扶稳了
Hold on, everybody!
我的天
God.
救命
My God!
抱歉
Sorry. Heh.
合作愉快
We make a good team.
尚恩 喂
Shaun. Hey.
告诉我刚才到底什么情况
You need to tell me what the hell's going on.
你在干嘛 你要去哪
What are you doing? Where are you going?
-澳门  -澳门?
-Macau. -Macau?
那些家伙要去找我妹妹
Those guys are going after my sister next,
我要在他们之前找到她
and I have to get to her first.
你还有个妹妹?
You have a sister?
我知道你现在很懵
Look, I know this is confusing.
我保证 回来之后会跟你解释的
I'll explain it when I get back, I promise.
不 不
No, no.
得了吧
Hell no, dude.
别给我在这扯蛋
This is bullshit!
我认识你小半辈子了
I have been by your side for half your life.
我明白有些事你不想说
I get there are things you never wanted to talk about,
我也从来不会去问
and I never wanted to push.
但是刚才一个胳膊上装着大砍刀的男的
But a guy with a freaking machete for an arm
把我们坐的巴士砍成了两半 尚恩
just chopped our bus in half, Shaun!
你到底是什么来头?
Who the hell are you?
我妹妹几个月前寄了这个给我
My sister sent me this a few months ago.
这上面的地址应就是她住的地方
I think it's the address of where she's staying.
刚才那些家伙是我父亲派来的
Those guys back there were sent by my dad.
什么
What?
要是他们再去伤害她...
If they hurt her...
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
好吧
Fine.
你可以在飞机上跟我解释
You can explain on the plane.
什么 不 凯蒂你别...
What? No, Katy, you can't just...
你可以在飞机上跟我解释清楚 尚恩
You can explain on the plane, Shaun!
妈妈去世后
After my mom died...
我爸爸就开始训练我
my dad started my training.
日复一日 日出到日落
From sunup to sundown,
我学尽各种杀人的方法
I was taught every possible way to kill a man.
14岁时
By the time I was 14,
我已经记不清
I could barely remember
妈妈还在时的生活是什么样了
what life was like before she died.
也就是那一年
That's how old I was
他派我去执行了第一个任务
when he sent me on my first assignment.
我原本愿意为他做任何事
I was willing to do anything he wanted.
就算他叫我把这个世界焚烧殆尽
If he asked me to burn the world down,
我也...
I would've asked him...
牛肉还是素食
Beef or vegetarian?
我们的鸡肉餐发完了
We're all out of the chicken,
所以只剩牛肉或者素食了
so I can only offer you beef or vegetarian?
唔...
Um...
-素食吧  -我也一样
-Vegetarian would be great. -Yeah, same.
好的 谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
所以...
So...
我们素食也没有了
We're out of the vegetarian too.
现在只有牛肉了
Now we only have beef.
那就牛肉 我们也没得选了不是吗
Beef. 'Cause that's all you have, right?
-好的 你要牛肉...  -嗯
-Okay, you'll have the beef. -Yes.
-那么...-牛肉
-And... -Beef.
-我也要牛肉  -好的 两份牛肉
-And the beef. -Two beefs.
那你执行完任务了吗?
Did you go through with it?
我知道我不能再回到他身边了 所以我只能...
I knew that I couldn't go back to him, so I just...
‪逃跑‬
ran.
我知道这些对你来说很难消化
I know this is a lot to dump on you.
你妈妈的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your mom.
还有一件事要告诉你
I should also probably mention
其实我的本名不是尚恩
that my name's not technically Shaun.
什么
What?
那你的名字是什么
What is it?
尚气
It's Shang-Chi.
双气
Shaun-Chi.
不 尚气
No. Shang-Chi.
爽气
Shaun-Chi.
尚
Shang.
-尚恩 -尚
-Shaun. -Shang.
擅
Shan.
Shi-ang-尚
S-H-A-N-G. Shang.
尚?
Shang?
对
Yeah.
你把尚改成了尚恩
You changed your name from Shang to Shaun?
对 我不...
Yeah, I don't... Yeah.
怪不得你爸能找到你
I wonder how your father found you.
我改名的时候才15岁 好吗
Okay, I was 15 years old. All right?
你是怎么想的?
What is your name change logic?
你打算隐姓埋名
You're going into hiding.
-对  -然后把自己的名字迈克尔
-Okay. -And your name is Michael,
改成了迈歇尔
you go on and change it to Mishael.
不 不是这么回事儿
That's not what happened.
就好像 嗨 我叫吉娜
It's like, "Hi, my name's Gina.
我要隐姓埋名了 我的新名字是洁娜
"I'm gonna go into hiding. My new name's Gina."
听不见了 不好意思
Can't hear you. I'm sorry.
哈 你听不到才怪
Yeah, okay. Yeah, you can hear me.
签字
Sign here to get in.
我在找我的妹妹 徐夏灵
I'm looking for my sister, Xu Xialing.
听说过她吗
Have you heard of her?
这里是她给我的地址
This is the address she gave me.
好的吧
Okay.
他看起来人挺好的
Seems like a nice fella.
这架电梯也肯定符合安全规范
And this elevator is definitely up to code.
绝对不会一下子掉到楼底
There's absolutely no chance of it just falling off
或者...
the side of the building...
公车男孩
Bus Boy!
哇靠 你三天就两百万播放量
Two million views in three days, bro!
靠 老铁
Damn, dude.
不妙
No.
哇 司机也来了 你的车技实在是太帅了
And you're the driver!
我中文不好
My Chinese sucks.
没事
All good.
-我能说点英文  -那太好了
- I speak A-B-C. - Great.
-我叫庄庄  -庄庄
-I'm Jon Jon. -Jon Jon.
欢迎来到金匕首俱乐部
Welcome to the Golden Daggers Club.
好 我带你去做热身
Okay, let's get you ready to fight.
等等 什么
Wait. What?
我们是全球多平台运营
We're a multi-platform global operation.
每场打斗都在暗网上直播
Every fight livestreamed on the dark web.
我们说话的这会功夫 成千上万的观众在下注
Thousands of viewers placing bets as we speak.
我们会带你走上人生巅峰
This is gonna take your brand to a whole new level.
我有点糊涂了
Think there's been some sort of confusion.
我喜欢他们的钉子脸
I like your spike face.
谢了
Thanks!
按理来说 你得一路打到中心擂台
Usually, you gotta fight your way to centre ring,
但像你这样的格斗明星
but a viral star like you?
你可以破例晋级 宝贝
Front of line, baby.
我不是来打架的
I'm not here to fight anybody. Okay?
我来找我妹妹 徐夏灵
I'm looking for my sister, Xu Xialing.
没听说过
Never heard of her.
我们刚失去了一位选手
We just lost a fighter at the last minute,
所以下一个你上场
so you get the next slot.
打得不错 海伦
Nice one, Helen.
他真的要和这些人打架吗
Is he gonna be fighting in one of these?
不不不 这些都是最低级的比赛
No, no, no. These are like low-level fights.
你要打的人 在上面
You're gonna be fighting up there.
很痛诶 埃米尔
That hurt, Emil.
想尝尝有多痛吗
You want me to show you how it feels?
王 王 王
Wong! Wong! Wong!
干得漂亮 王
Go, Wong!
我永远都押亚洲人赢
I always bet on Asian.
我的天哪
My God.
好吧 我不会到擂台上去的 好吗
Yeah, look, I'm not going up there, okay?
-我只是来...  -唔喔 唔喔 唔喔
-I'm just trying to... -Whoa, whoa, whoa.
现在后悔太晚了
It's too late to back out now.
-你已经同意了 兄弟  -什么?
- You already committed, bro. - What?
你签了合同 记得吗
You signed the contract, remember?
你的名字在花名册上
Your name's on the roster.
赌局已经悄然开始了
The bets are piling in.
-真的吗?我们能分多少钱?  -超多
- Really? What's our cut? - It's huge.
没所谓的好吗
It doesn't matter.
非常有所谓
It matters.
老兄 我看到你和五个杀手
Dude, I saw you fight five assassins
其中还有一个胳膊装砍刀的罗马尼亚巨人
and a giant Romanian with a razor for an arm
在行驶的车上搏斗
on a moving bus.
现在只要打一个人就行了
This is just one guy.
上吧 这样我们都能拿到钱了
Just do it. Then we all get paid,
然后我来帮你找你要找的人
and then I'll help you find whoever you're looking for.
上 你能行的
Come on. You got this.
-你可以的  -别紧张
- You got this. - Don't be nervous.
谢谢你嗷
Thank you.
-客气  -客气
- Yeah. - Yeah.
你的下巴还好吗
How's the jaw?
你得像练习的时候那样
Maybe you'll start controlling those punches
控制出拳
like we practised?
那个人真不错
Love that guy.
现在 把衣服脱了
Now take your shirt off.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们期待已久的对决即将开始
the fight we've all been waiting for.
轰动全网的
The incredible viral sensation,
从美国旧金山远道而来的
all the way from San Francisco, USA,
公车男孩
it's Bus Boy!
你衣服呢
What happened to your shirt?
而他今晚的对手
And his opponent for tonight,
正是我们澳门令人闻风丧胆的杀手
it's Macau's own fearsome killer...
徐夏灵
Xu Xialing!
灵灵
Sister.
等等 等一下
Wait, wait!
你怎么了你
What are you doing?
我知道你在生我的气
I know you're upset.
但是我有急事跟你...
But can you hear me out?
没有时间打了
We don't have time for this.
喔 肯定很疼
Ooh, that's gotta hurt.
你能不能不打我
Can you please stop hitting me?
住手 我是来帮你的
Stop it! I'm trying to help you!
爸要来找你
Dad's coming for you.
我不会再跟你打了
I'm not fighting you.
你不应该回来的
You shouldn't have come back.
有的时候 我在练功
Sometimes when I'm doing my forms...
我闭上我的眼睛
I close my eyes,
就可以感觉 她就在我身后
and it's like I can feel her.
你有这个感觉吗
Do you ever feel like that?
没有
No.
我知道你为什么要去那儿
I know what you're going there to do.
我不知道他跟你说了什么 但是妈妈...
I don't know what he's telling you, but Mom...
妈妈已经死了
Mom's dead.
不要把我扔在这
Please don't leave me here.
灵灵 我三天以后就回来
I'll be back in three days.
徐夏灵 太精彩了
Xu Xialing, you're amazing!
我们爱你 徐夏灵
We love you, Xu Xialing! Whoo!
这地方归你管?
You run this place?
这地方归我
I own it.
你这些钱是哪里来的
Where'd you get all that money?
你押我输?
Did you bet against me?
没有啊
No.
徐夏灵 我是凯蒂
Hi, Xialing. I'm Katy.
你真是酷毙了
You're, like, such a badass.
每个动作都堪称经典
Everything that you do is, like, so cool.
太酷了
That was really cool.
你的裤子很好看
I like your pants.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thanks. Yeah.
你来干什么
What do you want?
十环帮在旧金山伏击了我们
The Ten Rings ambushed us in San Francisco.
我看到视频了
I saw the video.
他们拿走了我的项链
They took my pendant.
他们的下一个目标就是你
They're gonna come for yours next.
我摸不准他现在到底想干吗
I don't know what he wants with them,
但肯定不是什么好事
but we both know it can't be good.
你知道他临走前跟我说什么吗?
You know what he said to me when he left?
三天后我就会回来
"I'll be back in three days."
三天后
And after three days,
我去妈妈的祠堂等他
I went to our mom's shrine and waited.
三天变成一星期
Three days turned into a week,
一星期变成一个月
a week turned to a month,
一个月变成六年
and a month turned to six years.
我才渐渐意识到
That's how long it took me to realise
我不再需要他了
I didn't need him any more.
我凭一己之力打造了这个地方
I built this place on my own.
那个时候我不需要你 现在就更不需要了
I didn't need you then, and I don't need you now.
那你为什么给我寄那张明信片
Then why would you send me the postcard?
什么明信片
What postcard?
这个不是我寄的
I didn't send you this.
这里有后门吗
Is there a back exit?
尚恩
Shaun.
嘿 嘿 嘿 开门
Hey. Hey! Hey, open up!
她已经跑了 兄弟
She's gone, dude.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
快点
Come on!
不会吧 去你的 我绝对不会干这档事的
Hell no. Screw you! I'm not doing this.
如果我们能到电梯那
If we make it to the elevator,
就能接着跳进下一层
we can hop in on the next floor.
没有别的办法了 凯蒂 现在就得下去
Katy, we're out of options. We have to go now.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
唔喔
Whoa.
往电梯跑 别回头
Just head straight for that elevator.
你可以的
You got this.
我给你争取点时间 你继续走
I'll buy you some time. Just keep going.
♪ 夜色下的沙漠公路上 ♪
On a dark desert highway
♪ 寒风拂过我的发梢 ♪
Cool wind in my hair
尚恩
Shaun!
尚恩 尚恩
Shaun! Shaun!
我的天
My God!
我来了
I'm coming!
尚恩
Shaun!
坚持住
Hang on.
拉住你了
Gotcha.
尚恩
Shaun!
凯蒂
Katy!
把我丢在这说走就走
You left us for dead!
现在你知道什么滋味儿了
Now you know how it feels.
他要这个项链做什么?
What does he want with the pendant...
在美国呆了几年 胆儿也变小了?
Did America make you soft?
项链在他手上
He has the pendant!
我跟我手下说过
I told my men
你要是动起真格来就杀不了你 他们不相信
they wouldn't be able to kill you if they tried.
还好我是对的
Glad I was right.
我很想你 我的儿子
I've missed you, my son.
咱们回家吧
Let's go home.
我的儿子回家了
My son is home.
把姑娘们带去她们的房间
Take the girls to their room.
我这周经历了许多心惊胆战的事
I've seen some really scary stuff this week,
但跟你爸相比 真是小巫见大巫
but your dad's on, like, a whole 'nother level.
他会杀了我们吗?
Is he gonna kill us?
只要言听计从 不多说话 他会忘记你的存在
Just nod. Don't talk. He'll forget you're there.
这便是我的生存之道
That's how I survived.
他一直都这么对你吗?
He always treat you like that?
从我母亲去世后开始
Only after my mom died.
他说他无法直视我 因为看着我总会想起母亲
He said he couldn't look at me because I reminded him of her.
他不允许我与男孩子一起训练
I wasn't allowed to train with the boys.
但我看过他们所有的训练内容
But I watched everything they did
我要求自己做得比他们更好
and taught myself to do it better.
那你什么时候离开的?
When did you leave?
我16岁的时候逃离了这里
I ran away when I was 16.
当我知道我哥不会再回来的时候
As soon as I knew my brother wasn't coming back.
所以你16岁的时候
You started an underground fight ring in Macau
就在澳门开了家地下竞技场?
when you were 16 years old?
如果父亲不让我染指他的帝国
If my dad won't let me into his empire,
我就建一个自己的帝国
I'm gonna build my own.
你太牛了
Hell yeah.
尚气
Shang-Chi.
可以了
That's enough.
你最近有在练习英语吗?
Have you been practicing your English?
练了
Yes.
你一定要在强健身体的同时磨练自己的心智
You have to strengthen your mind along with your body.
如果你想拥有它们
If you want them to be yours one day,
就必须向我证明你足够强大
you have to show me you're strong enough to carry them.
你是怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
我一直知道我的孩子在哪里
I always know where my children are.
我给了你十年时间让你去过自己的生活
I gave you 10 years to live your life,
你收获了什么呢?
and where did it get you?
是时候回到我身边了
Now it's time for you to take your place by my side.
不可能
That's not gonna happen.
美国妞
American girl.
她叫凯蒂
Her name is Katy.
那你的中文名字叫什么?
What is your Chinese name?
瑞文
Ruiwen.
名字是很神圣的 瑞文
Names are sacred, Ruiwen.
它联结的不仅是我们自身
They connect us not only to ourselves,
还有我们的先人
but to everyone who came before.
有个很有趣的故事
A funny story.
几年前 一个美国的恐怖分子
Some years ago, a terrorist from America
需要一个坏蛋
needed a boogeyman
来摧毁你们的国家
to bring your country to its knees.
所以他盗用了十环这个名字
So, he appropriated The Ten Rings.
我的十环
My Ten Rings.
但是他不知道我的真名 就自己起了一个
But because he didn't know my actual name,
就自己起了一个
he invented a new one.
你们知道他最后起了个什么名字吗
Do you know the name he chose?
满大人（有"柑橘"义）
The Mandarin.
他给他的名号起了个水果名
He gave his figurehead the name of a chicken dish.
居然还很管用
And it worked.
整个美国都陷入恐慌
America was terrified.
只是因为一只"橘子"
Of an orange.
其实我这一生
The truth is,
有过很多名字
I've had many names throughout my life.
战王 可汗大师
The Warrior King, Master Khan,
地球上最危险的人
the most dangerous man on Earth.
有很长一段时间 我以为这就是我人生的意义
For years, I thought that was all I was meant to be.
但自从我遇到了他们的妈妈以后
But when I met their mother,
一切都变了
everything changed.
她让我发现了新的自己
She showed me a part of myself I didn't know was there.
让我重新认识了这个世界
It was like I was seeing the world for the first time.
为了和我在一起 她抛下了一切
She gave up everything so we could be together.
而我也是一样
And so did I.
这是谁呀
You know who's in there?
你说 你好 妹妹
Say, "Hello, little sister!"
过了这么多年
After all those years,
我终于找到了
I finally found something
值得我为其变老的东西
worth growing old for.
我的真名叫文武
My real name is Wenwu.
她是唯一一个这么叫我的人
She was the only one who called me that.
在她离世以后
And when she died...
我迷失了很久
I was lost for many years.
但现在不会了
But I'm not lost any more.
当时你们两个离家出走
When you children ran away,
我迫切需要你们母亲灵魂的指引
I was so desperate to connect with your mother,
我全身心地投入到对她家乡的研究中
I threw myself back into the studies of her village.
传说中的塔罗
The legendary Ta Lo.
我没能找到
I wasn't able
通往村子入口的秘密路线
to find the secret path to the village entrance,
但我发现了他们到底在隐藏的东西
but I did find what they are hiding.
在那座大山的深处有一道门
There's a gate deep in their mountains.
你们的母亲就在那里等着我们
Your mother is waiting for us there.
我知道这很难接受
I know this is a lot.
如果不是她亲口告诉我 我也不敢相信
I might not have believed it if she didn't tell me herself.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
当时我坐在这张椅子上
I was sitting right here in this seat,
全神贯注地做着研究
deep in my research...
然后她和我说话了
and she spoke to me.
就好像她真的在这个房间里一样
It was like she was standing in this room.
我能感受到她的呼吸拂过我的脸颊
I could feel her breath on my cheek
手掌抚在我的背上
and her hand on my back.
她告诉我 她需要我的帮助
She told me she needs my help.
怎么帮?
To do what?
从她族人的手中救出她
To save her from her people.
我们坠入爱河之后
After we fell in love,
你母亲希望我们定居塔罗
your mother wanted us to live in Ta Lo.
她请求长老们的允准
She asked permission from the elders,
长者们却拒绝了
and they refused.
他们说我不配
They said I wasn't worthy.
如果没有被拒绝
She would still be with us.
她就不会死 我们就会一起在那里生活
We would all be living there together.
是塔罗害了我们
Ta Lo did this to us.
他们把她关在那扇大门后面 以示惩罚
They locked her behind that gate to punish her.
你还没看出来吗
Don't you see?
她给我们留下了线索
She's leaving clues for us.
她希望我们找到她
She wants us to find her
带她回家 一家团圆
and bring her home, so we can be a family again.
爸 妈已经走了
Dad, Mom's gone.
她并没有在大门后和你对话
She's not talking to you from behind a gate,
她也没有给我们留下任何线索
and she's not leaving any clues for us.
那这些是什么?
Then what are these?
去塔罗的通道被移动的迷宫守卫着
The passage to Ta Lo is guarded by a moving maze.
但是森林中有一条直达的路径
But there's a direct path through the forest
一年仅开放一次
that only opens once a year
在清明节的时候
on Qingming Jie.
要想通过 只有知道路线
To get through, you need to know the route
和开放的具体时间
and the exact time it opens.
现在我都知道了
Now I know both.
三天之后
Three days from now,
我们会救出我的夫人
we will rescue my wife from her prison
带她回家
and bring her home.
这就是你来这里的理由
This is why you're here.
帮我把她带回我们身边
To help me bring her back to us.
如果他们不让你打开大门怎么办?
And what happens if they don't let you open the gate?
那我们就把村子夷为平地
We'll burn the village to the ground.
什么?
What?
你不能就这样带兵攻打母亲的村庄
You can't just march into our mom's village
这太荒唐了
with this bullshit.
你知不知道这有多疯狂...
I mean, do you have any idea how insane...
嘿
Hey!
你们要带我去哪儿?
Where are you taking me?
你还要装多久
When will you stop pretending?
把他们关起来
Lock them up.
没关系
It's okay, my dear.
咱们一家人很快就能在一起了
We're all going to be together soon.
所以说 咱就是说 有点迷惑了
So, um, pretty confused right now,
因为我一开始觉得
because, initially I thought your dad should
你爸有妄想症必须去看心理医生
definitely see a therapist for his delusions,
但之后那个龙头 像施了法一样 喷出来一幅水做的地图
but then that dragon vomited a magical water map,
所以我现在都不知道什么才是真的了
and now I have no idea what's real.
关于你母亲家乡的那些话是真的吗?
Is what he said about your mom's village true?
我们小的时候
She used to tell us stories about Ta Lo
她曾经讲过塔罗的故事
when we were kids.
那是处于另一个空间的村庄 到处都是奇幻生物
A village in another dimension full of magical creatures.
我之前只当作神话故事
I thought it was just a fairy tale.
但如果爸说的是真的呢?
What if Dad's right?
你是说如果妈真的
About Mom being locked behind a gate
被自己的族人关起来了?
by her own people?
比这更疯狂的事情都已经发生了
Crazier things have turned out to be true.
听我说 我不知道这一切都他妈是怎么回事
Look, I don't know what the hell is going on,
但如果我们不杀出去并在他之前找到塔罗
but if we don't find a way to get to Ta Lo before him,
他会把咱们家仅剩的都毁掉的
he's gonna destroy everything that's left of our family.
这个家很久之前就已经被毁了
This family was destroyed a long time ago.
什么鬼
The hell was that?
你们真的要朝那个声音的方向去?
You're going toward that noise?
「麦克白」"敲醒邓肯吧
"Wake Duncan with thy knocking.
但愿你能够如此
"I would'st though could'st.
不想我所为 我最好忘掉（自己）"
"My deed 'twere best not..."
你们好啊 小可爱们
Hello, loves.
现在是哪一年了?
What year is it?
你是谁?
Who are you?
特雷弗?斯莱特里?
Trevor? Slattery?
来自利物浦的演员?
The actor from Liverpool?
等等
Wait.
你们是那位掌权者的孩子吗?
Are you the governor's kids?
我一直在为你们的接风宴
I've been preparing a monologue
准备一场独白话剧
for your homecoming dinner.
她要去哪
Where's she going?
你为什么在这下面?
Why are you down here?
是这样 很久之前
Well, some time ago,
我接到一个恐怖分子的角色
I was offered the role of a terrorist.
我知道 这个剧情老套又无聊 我也这么觉得
I know, facile, trite, I couldn't agree more.
但是机不可失 失不再来 你知道吗
But times were lean, you know what I mean?
总之就是 制作人说他是BBC的
Anyway, the producer told me he worked for the BBC.
但是 讽刺的转折来了
But, ironic twist,
结果 其实 他真的是个恐怖分子
it turns out he, in fact, was a terrorist,
我当时根本不是在扮演一个角色
and I wasn't playing a character at all,
我知道我说的话
but what I now recognise to be
你会觉得我在说你爸坏话
a rather unflattering portrait of your father.
我们都罪有应得
We all got our just deserts.
那个制片人被钢铁侠炸飞了
The producer got blown up by Iron Man,
我也在联邦监狱服了刑
and I served time in federal prison,
不过对我来说反而是个好事
which turned out to be the best thing for me.
我戒了毒 重拾了我热爱的表演
I got clean, I rediscovered my passion.
-然后我爸把你救出来了? -没错
-Then my dad broke you out? -Exactly.
-为了杀你 -没错
-To kill you. -Exactly.
但是 在他的手下
But just as his men
即将把我绑起来处死时
were tying me up for my execution,
我表演了一段《麦克白》
I launched into a performance of my Macbeth.
「麦克白」"哪来的敲门声?敲醒邓肯吧!
"Whence is that knocking? Wake Duncan
"但愿你能够如此!"
"with thy knocking. I would'st though could'st..."
他们简直百看不厌
They couldn't get enough of it.
从那以后 我就一直为他们表演
I've been doing weekly gigs for the lads ever since.
所以你是他的小丑?
So you're like his jester?
你想看的话 我给你模仿一下
I can give you a quick preview if you like.
"叔叔 叔叔 叔叔..."
"Nuncle, nuncle, nuncle..."
谢谢你 特雷弗 我觉得可以了
Thank you, Trevor. I think we're okay.
现在我们只想找到出去的路
Right now, we really just need to find a way to...
什么情况?
What the hell?
什么...
What the...!
-唔喔  -那是个什么玩意?
-Whoa! -What is that?
那是个什么玩意?
What's what?
-那个 那是个什么玩意?  -那个 那个 那个
-That! What is that? -That! That! That!
你们能看到莫里斯?
You can see Morris?
莫里斯?
Morris?
莫里斯
Morris!
他们看得到你 你真的存在
They can see you! You're real!
这么长时间以来 我以为他是我臆想出来的
All this time I thought I was hallucinating him.
真是太好了
This is such fab news.
他的脸在哪里?
Where's his face?
他对这个话题有点敏感
He's a bit sensitive about that.
哦 是么?
Really?
莫里斯说他知道你是谁
Morris says he knows who you are.
他...他会跟你说话?
It talks... It talks to you?
如果不是他和我说话
If he didn't talk to me,
我早就疯了
I'd have gone mad yonks ago.
他是怎么认识我的?
How would he know me?
他说 在塔罗的时候 他和你母亲一起长大
He says he grew up with your mum. In Ta Lo.
你爸爸寻找入口的时候
Apparently, your father picked him up in some magic forest
在奇幻森林里捡到了他
on one of his expeditions to find the entrance.
他希望你能带他回家
He wants you to take him home.
相信我 朋友 如果我知道该怎么做 我一定会的
Believe me, buddy, I would if I knew how.
我爸说
According to my dad,
这条路一年只打开一次
the path there only opens once a year.
莫里斯说他现在就可以带你去
Morris says he can guide you there right now.
不用等那条路打开
You can get through the maze
他就能带你穿过迷宫
without waiting for the path to open.
但是 有一个很大的"但是"
But, and it's a big "but,"
此行非常危险
it's very dangerous.
有多危险?
How dangerous?
没有人能活着从那里面出来
No one's ever made it out alive.
但是莫里斯百分之九十确定
But Morris is 90% confident
他能够带我们安全地通过
he can guide us through safely.
百分之十九
19%.
我做过比这更蠢 风险更高的事情
Look, I've done dumber things with worse odds.
但是即使那个长得像鸡的猪说的是真的...
But even if that chicken-pig is right...
...我们仍然困在这里...
...we're still locked in your...
你是怎么...
How did you...
爸爸在整个院子下面造了隧道系统
Dad has a tunnel system under the whole compound.
我上一次就是这么逃跑的
That's how I escaped last time.
这里直接通向车库
This will take us straight to the garage.
哦我的天
My God.
这车真不错
I kinda like this guy.
下斜坡直走到大门
Just head up that ramp and through the front gate.
直接就到了
Should be a straight shot.
我们大概有三十秒的时间
Figure we got about 30 seconds until he...
介意我坐前排吗
Do you mind?
我坐后排会有点晕 晕车
I get sick in the back. Carsick.
那是我的车啊
That's my car!
该死
God damn it.
抓紧了
Hold on.
还有其他出口吗
Is there another exit?
在车库的另一头
The other end of the garage.
但是是指纹解锁开门的
But we need a fingerprint to open it.
小心
Incoming!
靠
Shit!
后面怎么样
What's happening back there?
我在尽力
Doing my best.
请扫描掌纹解锁开门
Scan hand print for gate access.
-快点  -我正在
- Hurry up! - I'm trying!
请扫描掌纹解锁开门
Scan hand print for gate access.
尚恩
Shaun!
已解锁
Access approved.
只要我带她回家 他们肯定会回来
They will come back once I bring her home.
准备人手 随时应战
Prepare the men for war.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我第一次看到纯粹的艺术
The first time I witnessed pure artistry.
是在1968年看《人猿星球》的时候
1968. Planet of the Apes.
我和母亲坐在电影院里
I was sitting in the cinema next to my mum,
聚精会神地
watching mastery
观看那部杰作
unfold before my very eyes.
看完之后 我问她
After the film, I asked her,
他们是怎么让猴子做这些事的
"How did they get those monkeys to do those things?"
她拍了拍我的头 说
And she patted me on the head and she said,
那都是假的 只是表演而已
"It's not real, pet. It's just acting."
从那时起我就觉得
That's when I knew.
如果他们可以教那些猴子
If they can teach those monkeys
表演得出神入化
to act that brilliantly,
这么想想 我可以为这个世界带来什么
just imagine what I could bring to the world.
所以你成为了一名演员
So you became an actor
因为你以为那些猴子真的
because you thought the monkeys were actually...
我以为它们真的在骑马 是的
Riding horses? I did. Yes.
但实际上
When, in fact,
它们只是在表演而已 演得好像它们真的在骑马一样
they were simply acting as if they were riding horses.
不过说实话我到现在都没整明白是怎么做到的
I still can't get my head round it, to be honest.
真有你的 兄弟
Good for you, dude.
你找到了你的热爱所在
You found your passion and went for it,
为它付出
and eventually used it
并凭一己之力削弱了美国政府 但不管怎样
to cripple the US government, but whatever.
啊 是的 谢谢啊
Yeah. No, yeah, thanks.
真不错
Um, this is really cool and all,
但我们还要在这里坐多久
but how long do we have to sit here?
莫里斯非常清楚
Morris is very clear.
万事俱备 只欠东风
The way through is all about timing.
好的 但我们还要在这聊多久
Okay, but how long are we talking?
几个小时?还是几天?
Like, hours? Days?
朋友们 我只是个临时容器而已
Friends, I am but a transitory vessel
用来承载生命无穷的智慧
for the infinite wisdom of a creature
这无穷智慧远比我们可以理解的先进得多
far more advanced than we'll ever truly understand.
他在这个广袤未知的宇宙里
What he sees, what he feels
看到的 感受到的东西
of this vast, unknown universe
是我们简单的头脑无法容纳的
is beyond anything our simple brains can...
可以动身了
You can go.
什么
What?
出发 它说你们可以出发了
Go. You can go. He says "go."
你应该开快点
You should speed up.
啊 为什么
What? Why?
凯蒂 快 开快点 快
Katy, go, go, go!
莫里斯说
Morris says,
-三秒钟后方向盘向右打死  -啥
-"Hard right on three." -What?
二
Two...
哪里开始右转啊
Hard right where?
现在
Now.
然后左转
And left.
这一切都是为了留在口袋里
It's all about staying in the pocket.
-什么口袋  -我们现在就在这里面
-What pocket? -We're in it now.
要是我们没留在这里会怎么样
What happens if we don't stay in the pocket?
那样森林就会吃了我们
The forest eats us.
吃了我们 什么意思
Eats us? What does that mean?
它说的就是森林会吃了我们 左转
He says it eats us. Go left.
-小心后面  -待在口袋里
- Watch your back! - Stay in the pocket.
-还有多远?  -五米
- How close is it? - Five metres.
-待在口袋里  -五米是多少尺
- Stay in the pocket. - What is that in feet?
超他妈近了
Really fricking close.
待在口袋里
Stay in the pocket.
你能不能别说待在口袋里了
Will you just stop saying, "Stay in the pocket"?
最后一次转向 马上就要结束了
One last right, then straight on to the end.
你最好快一点
You might wanna hurry up.
不然你以为我在逛街吗
What do you think I'm doing?
要来不及了
We're not gonna make it.
我马上回"家"见你 妈妈
I'm coming home, Mummy.
莫里斯说 "干得漂亮 各位"
Morris says, "Great job, everyone."
现在我们只要穿过瀑布
Now, all we have to do is go through that waterfall,
就到了
and we're pretty much there.
妈的
Bloody hell.
这些鸟是着火了吧
I think those birds are on fire.
真的诶
Really?.
莫里斯说这很正常
Morris says it's normal.
他们是他旧时的伙伴
They're old mates of his.
这马长的真别致
That's a weird horse.
它为什么看着我?
What's it looking at me for?
大家好
Hi there!
我是徐尚气
I am Xu Shang-Chi.
这是我妹妹 徐夏灵
This is my sister, Xu Xialing.
我们是映丽的孩子
We're Ying Li's children.
这是我的朋友凯蒂
This is my friend, Katy.
上车 哪来的回哪去
Get in your car and go home!
你误会了 请听我们说
Please. You don't understand.
唔喔
Whoa.
光伯
Guang Bo!
这是在干什么?
What are you doing?
放下你们的武器
Put down your weapons!
尚气
Shang-Chi.
夏灵
Xialing.
我是你们的小姨 映南
I'm your aunty Nan.
终于见到你了
I've waited so long to meet you.
像你妈妈
You look like your mother.
你好 我是凯蒂
Hi, I'm Katy.
欢迎来到塔罗 凯蒂
Welcome to Ta Lo, Katy.
谢谢
Thank you.
看看谁回来了
Look who has found his way home!
我人畜无害
I'm not a threat.
就是个杂耍的
Just an entertainer.
莫里斯可以替我担保
Morris can vouch for me.
我们没多少时间了
We don't have much time.
父亲就要来了
Our father is coming.
我们已经在这里待了四千年
Our people have been here for over 4,000 years,
来准备应对一些我们永远不希望发生的事情
preparing for something we hope will never happen.
我们是黑暗之门的守卫者
We are the keepers of the Dark Gate,
誓死保卫这片土地和你们的家园
sworn to protect this realm and yours
不受到困在门后的恶魔的伤害
from the evil that's locked behind it.
我们的父亲就是来打开那扇门的
Our dad is coming here to open that gate.
他认为你们把我们的妈妈关在那里
He thinks you're holding our mom there.
他怎么会这么想
Why would he think that?
妈妈告诉他的
She told him.
他说他能听到妈妈在向他求救
He says he can hear her asking for help.
他一直戴着十环吗
Is he wearing the rings?
自从妈妈死后他从来没有取下来过
He hasn't taken them off since she died.
十环和这一切有什么关系
What do they have to do with all this?
塔罗的领土一直延伸到
The realm of Ta Lo stretches far beyond
我们小村庄的海岸线之外
the shores of our small village.
我们的城市胜过你们宇宙中的任何一座城市
We have cities that surpass any in your universe,
孕育着非常丰富的文化和历史
rich with culture and history.
几千年前
Thousands of years ago,
所有族人都过着和平繁荣的日子
all of our people lived in peace and prosperity,
直到遭受黑暗居民的袭击
until the attack of the Dweller-in-Darkness.
他带领他的军队
He came with his army,
吞噬了他们沿途经过的每一个灵魂
devouring every soul in their path,
每一次杀戮都使他们更为强大
and with each kill, they grew stronger.
在摧毁我们最大的城市之后
After decimating our largest cities,
他们又进军到你们的宇宙再次进行屠杀
they were headed to your universe to do the same.
塔罗的领袖派出了最强大的一批战士
The leaders of Ta Lo sent their strongest warriors here
去阻止他们到达通往你们世界的传送门
to stop them from reaching the portal to your world.
但是我们的祖先不是他们的对手
But our ancestors were no match for them.
直到守护者加入了这场战争
Until The Great Protector
并且扭转了局势
joined their fight and turned the tide.
他们共同奋力将黑暗居民军队
Together, they pushed the Dweller and his army
打进了黑暗之门
into the Dark Gate
并且将他们锁在了里面
and locked it behind them.
从那之后我们的族人就一直守卫着这道门
Our people have guarded that gate ever since,
守护者的魔力赋予了我们力量
empowered by the magic of The Great Protector
以及她送给我们的礼物
and the gift that she gave us.
龙鳞
Dragon scales.
能够做出上成盔甲
Makes very good armour.
在你父亲之前有很多人来到这
Your father isn't the first to come here
想要打开黑暗之门
to open the Dark Gate.
几个世纪以来这些人不断尝试又不断失败
Many have tried and failed over the centuries,
他们都有一个共同点
and they all had one thing in common.
他们都被另一个世界的
They were lured here
某种声音吸引着
by the voice of something on the other side.
一种承诺满足他们最强欲望的声音
A voice that promised them their greatest desires.
所以你认为是噬魂者在和我们的父亲交谈?
So you think soul eaters are talking to our dad?
他们知道十环有能力让他们重获自由
They know The Ten Rings have the power to break them free.
给你
Here you go.
去射箭场
To the range.
啥? 好吧
What? Okay.
呃 看来我要送些龙箭过去了
Um, looks like I'm gonna go deliver some dragon arrows.
你要送这些龙箭过去?
You're gonna deliver some dragon arrows?
嗯 我也得干点事
Yeah. Make myself useful, you know.
谢谢
Thank you.
去看看你母亲吧
Let's go see your mother.
好羡慕你们知道自己想要做什么
I just love how you guys know exactly what you wanna do,
然后用一生的时间来精通它
and you spend your whole life getting really good at it.
我希望也能和你们一样
I wish I was more like that.
但是好像每次我稍微擅长一些事情
It's like every time I get moderately good at something,
我就会半途而废 然后尝试新的事物
I just quit and start something new.
我知道自己的极限
But I just know my own limits,
所以我不会浪费时间去追求一些
and I'm not gonna waste my time chasing something
最终会让我失望的事情
that will ultimately be a disappointment for me.
那不是我
That's not me.
光伯
Guang Bo.
让她试试
Let her shoot.
如果你心中没有靶子 就是无的放矢
If you aim at nothing, you hit nothing.
你们曾经是她的一切
You were everything to her.
她知道你们总有一天会到这里来找她
She knew that one day you would find your way here
所以她让我为你们的到来做了准备
and asked me to prepare something for your arrival.
失去她这样优秀的人之后
After losing someone like her,
很容易会觉得活着很孤独
it's easy to feel alone in this world.
但你们没有
But you're not.
你们是这个家的子女
You are children of this family,
我欢迎你们回家
and I welcome you home.
这里不是你父亲家
You're not in your father's house any more.
在塔罗 每个人都可以练武
In Ta Lo, we train as equals.
是时候从影子里走出来了 孩子
You've been in the shadows long enough, my child.
光伯 你看到了吗
Guang Bo, you saw that?
我射得相当不错吧
That was tight!
我母亲是唯一一个可以打败我父亲的人
My mother was the only one who could beat him.
告诉我她是如何做到的
Show me how she did it.
不 停一下
No, sorry.
抱歉 越位了 越位了
Sorry. Offside, offside.
你妈妈知道她自己是谁
Your mother knew who she was.
你知道自己是谁吗
Do you?
你是所有前人的产物
You are a product of all who came before you.
你是家族的遗产 无论好的坏的
The legacy of your family, the good and the bad,
都是构成你的一部分
it is all a part of who you are.
别再逃避了 外甥
Stop hiding, nephew.
这样只会让你沉湎于痛苦
It only prolongs the pain.
我们很快就能团聚了
We'll be together soon.
先生
Sir.
人手准备好了
The men are ready.
通道将在黎明时打开
The passage will open at dawn.
我会准备好车
I'll prepare the vehicles.
以心行气
Lead with your breath.
以气运身
Look into your heart,
要先掌握阴阳的转换
the light and the dark.
你才能找到内心的平衡
To know yourself,
从而真正认识自己
you must face them both.
你丈夫想灭了我了我的门
Your husband tried to destroy us.
我们今天是来回礼的
The Iron Gang is here to repay that debt.
他已经不是以前的那个人了
My husband is not the man he used to be.
那我不管
It doesn't matter.
你们之间的事情跟我的孩子们无关
Your business with him has nothing to do with my children.
放了他们可以
They can go,
但这个礼 必须得有人来接吧
but someone has to pay.
灵灵 尚气
Xialing. Shang-Chi.
进屋去
Go inside.
我跟客人有话要说
I'm going to talk to our guests.
可你现在没有魔法了呀
But you don't have your powers.
尚气 别怕
Shang-Chi, you have nothing to fear.
妈妈
Mama.
爸爸
Papa.
她说我是可以改变的
She told me I could change.
我也可以放下以前
That I could leave my past behind.
可是她错了
But she was wrong.
如果我当初没有把它们摘下来
If I hadn't taken them off,
那些混蛋根本就不敢动手
those men wouldn't have dared to do this.
我要他们付出代价
And now they will pay for it.
你老板呢
Where's your boss?
我不知道
I don't know!
我真的不知道
I swear I don't!
那好
Okay.
血债必须要血偿
A blood debt has to be paid by blood.
你愿意帮爸爸吗
Will you help me?
我们找到
We found the man
害死你母亲的人了
responsible for killing your mother.
你有权为我们两个人了结这件事
It is your right to finish this for both of us.
你回来以后
And when you return,
他们会像以前一样对十环卑躬屈膝
we will rebuild The Ten Rings to what it once was.
我到处找你
Been looking everywhere for ya.
你还好吗
You okay?
我和你所想象的不一样
I'm not who you think I am.
你已经道过歉了
You already apologised for that. We're good...
我不是在说那个
That's not what I'm talking about.
好
Okay.
你...想说什么
What... What is it?
当时我爸爸让我去找杀害我妈妈的人
When my dad sent me to find the man who killed my mom...
我之前说我下不了手
I told you I couldn't go through with it.
我撒谎了
I lied.
我以为我可以改名
I thought that I could change my name,
然后开始新的生活 假装那些事都没发生过
start a new life, pretend like it never happened.
但...
But...
她一定会讨厌现在的我
She would hate the person I've become.
你七岁的时候
Your dad trained you to be an assassin
你爸就开始训练你成为一名杀手
when you were seven.
你十四岁的时候 他让你去杀人
He sent you on a hit at 14.
你也知道这很荒谬 对吧
You realise how messed up that is, right?
我妈妈被害死 都是因为他
My mom is dead because of him.
现在他还要毁了她的家乡
And now he's coming to destroy her home.
血债必须要血偿
A blood debt has to be paid by blood.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我要用他教我的本领
I'm gonna do what he trained me to do.
亲手杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
他来了
He's here.
不行
No!
你还没准备好
You're not ready.
她留下
She stays here.
你居然要帮
Are you here to help the people
监禁你母亲的人
holding your own mother captive?
她不在那
She isn't back there.
那个怪物在骗你
You're being lied to
它想毁灭我们所有人
by a creature who wants to destroy us all.
他们是这么跟你说的吗
Is that what they told you?
我清楚我妻子的声音
I know my wife's voice.
她是我姐姐 我和你一样想念她
I miss my sister as much as you do,
但用这种方式来纪念她 是不对的
but this is not the way to honour her memory.
你们纪念她的方式
Did you honour her when you turned her away
就是把她关在那扇门后面吗?
from your gate?
混账 我们拒绝的人是你
You fool. We turned you away.
你过去所造的孽 会毁了这个地方
The sins of your past would have destroyed this place.
小子 跟我讲话礼貌点
Be careful how you speak to me, young man.
我吃的盐比你吃的饭还要多
I've lived ten of your lifetimes.
让我过去
Let me pass.
不行
We cannot do that.
把这儿烧了
Burn it down.
拦住他!
Stop him!
你难道打算仅凭一己之力阻止我?
Are you planning to stop me all by yourself?
我不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
不 你怕得很
Yes, you are.
你这一生都在恐惧中度过
You've spent your entire life afraid.
抱头逃窜
Always running,
东躲西藏
always hiding.
他们找上她的时候 你就在旁边
You were there when they came for her,
但你什么都没做
and you did nothing.
光站在窗边 眼睁睁看着她死
You stood at a window and watched her die!
妈妈不在了 我们需要你
She was gone and we needed you.
但是你眼里只有那破臂环
But you chose those damn rings over us.
把自己的儿子训练成了杀手
You trained your son to be a killer.
你满意了吗?
Is this what you wanted?
就算你能带她回来
Even if you could bring her back,
你凭什么觉得 她还愿意和你扯上关系?
what makes you think she'd want anything to do with you?
来救我
Save me.
快来救我
Save me, my dear.
救我
Save me.
我们回家了
I'm coming, my love.
他在破坏门
He breached the gate!
不合作的话
Those things are gonna kill us all
我们都会命丧食魂怪之手
if we don't work together.
你难道我会信你的鬼话?
You think I'm going to fall for that?
你们的武器对付不了它们
Your weapons are useless against them.
我们不需要你们的帮助
We don't need your help.
我们可是无所不能的十环帮
We are the mighty Ten Rings,
才不需要...
and any...
我们...还是合作吧
We... We should work together.
放了他们
Release them.
都解开
Release them!
他们在做什么?
What are they doing?
把吸取的灵魂带回给门后还没出来的家伙
Stealing souls to feed the Dweller-in-Darkness.
等他积攒够了力量
If it grows strong enough,
就会直接冲破大门
it will break right through the gate.
那还只是开始
That was just the beginning.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
我要帮我的朋友
I have to help my friends.
活着回来
Don't die.
所有人马上到湖边集合 快
Everyone to the water now!
到湖边 快走
To the lake! Let's go!
快走
Let's go!
嘿 你哥哥在哪
Hey, where's your brother?
我还指望你知道
I was hoping you knew.
救我
Save me.
齐天共战 誓死如归
Aim at the sky, to win or die!
深吸一口气
Deep breath.
尚气 别怕
Shang-Chi, you have nothing to fear.
你有神龙之心
You have the heart of our dragon.
你是妈妈是血脉 也是爸爸的
I will always be a part of you. And your dad will too.
你要把我们给你的一切化成你自己的力量
Take everything we've given you and make it your own.
你是妈妈的骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
我们的家需要你
Our family needs you.
去吧
Go.
开弓
Draw.
放箭
Fire!
你得阻止你父亲
You have to stop your father!
她不在那里 爸爸
She's not back there, Dad.
别碍事 孩子
Get out of my way, boy.
不
No.
哥们 冷静
Calm down, mate.
我没死 是装的
I'm not dead, it's just a performance.
配合一下
Now get down here and play along.
我得救她
I have to save her.
她在呼唤我
She's calling to me.
我也希望是真的
I wish that were true.
爸爸 求求你
Dad, please.
你的家人需要你
Your family needs you.
放我出去
Let me out!
靠
Shit.
它朝着村子去了
It's headed for the village!
如果神龙的灵魂被吞掉了
If it gets our dragon's soul,
就什么都阻止不了他了
it will be unstoppable!
对准它的喉咙
Aim for the throat!
放手吧
You have to let me go.
放手
Let go!
我不会再离开你
I'm not leaving you again.
妈的牛逼
Holy shit.
去吧
Go.
今晚
Tonight,
我们缅怀那些为了我们
we honour those who gave their lives
而牺牲自己的人们
so we might see another day.
他们不仅是战士
They were more than warriors.
他们也曾为人父母
They were our mothers and fathers,
是我们的兄弟姐妹
our sisters and brothers.
我们会永远记得他们
And though we will always hold on to their memories,
今晚 他们要和祖先重聚了
tonight we release them to rest with our ancestors.
爸 走好
Farewell, Dad.
妈妈 放心吧
Mum, we'll be okay.
千年以前
A thousand years ago,
千年以后
and a thousand years from now,
他们会永远在一起
we will always be together.
我真的以为我们会死
I seriously thought we were going to die.
我才刚学会射箭
And I'd only learned how to shoot a bow,
不到一天
like, a day earlier,
现在我和尚恩的小姨一起
now I'm on a battlefield,
在战场上杀吸灵魂的怪物
killing all these Soul Suckers with Shaun's aunty,
肖恩的小姨简直就是狂霸酷炫的功夫女神
who's this awesome, magical kung fu goddess.
我当时正跟守护者
And I'm hanging on to The Great Protector
和我妹妹一起
with my sister at this point,
奋力抵抗巨大的噬魂者
trying not to get eaten by the Mega Soul Sucker.
那玩意儿真不是个东西
The Mega Soul Sucker was such a nasty bitch.
就是 它还想吸了我们神龙的魂
Yeah. It was trying to eat our dragon's soul.
一旦被它吸走
Which would have allowed it
得到的力量就足以毁灭整个世界
to destroy the entire universe.
是啊
Yeah.
我当时只剩一支箭了
I only had one arrow left,
我只能听到脑海里
and all I could hear in the back of my mind
我妈妈的声音响起
was my mom's voice saying,
"给我一箭中的 妈妈的小机灵鬼"
"Just take the shot, you little mooch!"
我就直接瞄准噬魂者的喉咙
And so, I aimed right for the Sucker's throat
-让龙箭飞  -她真的一箭中的
-and I let her fly. -She hit it dead on.
接着尚恩用十环
And then Shaun used the Ten Rings
搞出一个像龟派气功一样的大火球
to do this crazy Kamehameha fireball
把那玩意儿炸了
that exploded the thing...
于是他就拯救了世界
...and he saved the world.
唉 好多人牺牲了
Yeah, we, lost some good people that day...
但是我们成功了
but we made it.
没错 我们做到了
We made it.
你们有完没完 还要嘲讽我到什么时候
Are you done mocking me?
啊 没有啊 我们可没嘲讽你
No. We're not mocking you.
所以你那个妹妹 哪去了
So where is this sister of yours?
回我爸爸的帮派了
She's back at my dad's compound,
她要彻底解散那里
shutting down his operations.
对啊 他爸爸是
Yeah, his dad was the head of The Ten Rings
存在了几千年的十环帮的首领
for the past thousand years.
两周之前 你们还在靠停车赚小费
Two weeks ago, you were parking cars for tips,
现在你想让我相信 你打败了噬魂兽
and you want me to believe you're now saving the world
拯救了世界?
from soul-sucking monsters?
我懂了 你们是想为上回的事找补
I know, you're trying to get me back
但我并不打算为我的言论道歉
for what I said last time, but I'm not gonna apologise...
因为我拿你们当朋友才会这么说的
...for speaking the truth as a friend.
我说真的
I really meant what I said, and, in fact, I actually think
甚至觉得你们说的更加佐证了我的看法
this whole bit you're doing just further proves my point.
你们俩显然是...
You guys are obviously...
-干嘛  -尚气
- What? - Shang-Chi.
尚气
Shang-Chi.
这儿
Here.
到
Present.
我是王
My name is Wong.
啊 我知道 先生 我是你铁杆粉丝...
Yeah, I know, sir. I'm a huge fan...
你真的拥有十环吗
Do you have the rings?
嗯 对啊
Yeah, yes.
好 跟我走 我跟你还有很多话要说
Good. Let's go, we have a lot to talk about.
还有你
You too.
还有我的份?
Me too?
-我觉得咱们应该... -哦 对 没错
- I think we should... - Yeah.
-咱得走了 -走着
- We gotta go. - Yeah.
我懂 这事太难以接受了 之后跟你发短信解释
I know this is, like, crazy, but I'm gonna text you,
如果有机会的话 很高兴见到你 约翰
and we'll do this again. Nice to see you, John.
之后给你们转账...
I'll Venmo you for the...
独立日你开着敞篷车兜风
You was crusin' with your top down Fourth of July
我开着车 我们在红绿灯前停下
I was movin' down the block We got caught at the light
我想追求你
Out my window I was shooting my shot
看着天上的烟火
Watching fireworks in the sky
就是你了 就是你了
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
我爱上了你
I'm calling it now
你会爱上我
You'll find love with me somehow
就是你了
Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
夏天我们开着敞篷车 享受阳光
In the summers we let the top down Soak up the light
我只想锁定我今生所爱
All I wanted was just to lock down the love of my life
像午夜兜风一样简单美好
Nice and simple like a midnight drive
看着天上的烟火
Watching fireworks in the sky
就是你了 就是你了
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
我爱上了你
I'm calling it now
你会爱上我
You'll find love with me somehow
就是你了
Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
哦 哦 哦
Ooh, ooh, ooh
描绘你的每词每句
Every line, every word every noun and verb can define you
哦 哦 哦
Ooh, ooh, ooh
你很害羞但让我停车
You were shy but you told me to pull over
我在你身后
And now I'm right behind you
我们进展很快 但感觉很对
We was movin' kinda fast but the feeling was right
今晚就去内华达结婚
We should cruise up to Nevada Get married tonight
只要你在 生活就很简单
Life is simple as long as you're in my life
看着天上的烟火
Watching fireworks in the sky
就是你了 就是你了
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
我爱上了你
I'm calling it now
你会爱上我
You'll find love with me somehow
就是你了
Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
典籍里没有这样东西
They don't match any artefacts from our codex.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
不是振金 也许是齐塔瑞族的
They're not vibranium. Chitauri?
我没见过这样的外星技术
Not like any alien tech I've seen.
在交给你之前
How long did your dad have them
你爸拥有十环多久了
before he gave them to you?
呃
Um...
一千年吧
About a thousand years.
根据热释光来看
Their thermoluminescence indicates
十环的年龄不只一千年
they're older than that.
远超一千年
By a lot.
你第一次使用十环的时候
The first time you used the rings,
我们在卡玛泰姬就感觉到了
we felt it in Kamar-Taj.
这是什么
What is it?
一个信号
A beacon.
他们在发送信息
They're sending a message.
发到哪里
A message to where?
不好意思 我有事要处理
I'm so sorry. I have to deal with this.
布鲁斯有我的电话号码
You can get my number from Bruce.
很高兴见到你
It was so nice to meet you.
我没有她的号码
Yeah, I... I don't have her number.
她经常这样
She... She does this a lot.
注意安全
Guys, stay safe.
欢迎加入我们这个马戏团
Welcome to the circus.
要理解和消化的东西很多
I know this is a lot to take in,
但你得慢慢习惯
but you're gonna have to start getting used to that.
你们的人生轨道
From now on, the trajectory of your lives
已经彻底改变了
will be like nothing you've ever experienced before.
而且没有回头路
And there's no going back.
前路漫漫
You both have a long journey ahead of you.
回家好好休息
Go home, get some rest.
好主意
Yeah. That's a good idea.
对 该好好休息
Yeah. Yeah, we probably should do that.
或者
Or...
欢迎来到加州旅馆
Welcome to the Hotel California
-多么美丽的地方  -多么美丽的地方
-Such a lovely place -Such a lovely place
-多么可爱的脸庞  -多么可爱的脸庞
-Such a lovely face -Such a lovely face
加州旅馆有很多房间
Plenty of room at the Hotel California
-无论何时  -无论何时
-Any time of year -Any time of year
都可以来住
You can find it here
她爱慕虚荣
Her mind is Tiffany-twisted
开着奔驰
She got the Mercedes Benz,
有一群帅气的朋友
She got a lot of pretty, pretty boys she calls friends
他们在庭院跳舞 流着香汗
How they dance in the courtyard, sweet summer sweat
有的想铭记 有的想忘却
Some dance to remember, some dance to forget
我叫领班送点酒
So I called up the Captain "Please bring me my wine"
他说从1969年起就没有了
He said, "We haven't had that spirit here since 1969"
那些声音仍在召唤
And still those voices are calling from far away
在深夜叫醒你
Wake you up in the middle of the night
听他们说
Just to hear them say
欢迎来到加州旅馆
Welcome to the Hotel California
-多么美丽的地方  -多么美丽的地方
-Such a lovely place -Such a lovely place
多么可爱的脸庞
Such a lovely face
他们在加州旅馆纵情狂欢
They livin' it up at the Hotel California
-多么美妙的惊喜  -多么美妙的惊喜
-What a nice surprise -What a nice surprise
准备好借口
Bring your alibis
他们在等着了
They're waiting.
开始吧
Let's get started.
我们有很多事要准备
We have a lot of work to do.